There are common ways to notate
توجد طرق شائعة لتدوين معلمات،
parameters that are different than the way we notate statistics.
مختلفة عن الطريقة التي ندوّن بها الإحصائيات.
In general, parameters are notated with Greek symbols,
عادة ما يتم تدوين المعلمات بالرموز اليونانية،
where statistics are either notated by
حيث يتم تدوين الإحصائيات إمّا
lower case letters or the same Greek symbol with a hat on it.
بأحرف صغيرة أو بالرمز اليوناني نفسه مع وجود حرف إقحام عليه.
Here, this symbol called mu represents the mean of a population,
هنا، هذا الرمز يسمى mu ويمثل متوسط السكان،
while these represent the mean of a sample.
بينما تمثل هذه متوسط العينة.
Similarly, this Greek symbol called
وبالمثل، يسمى هذا الرمز اليوناني
sigma represents the standard deviation of a population,
sigma ويمثل الانحراف المعياري للسكان،
while either of these can be used to represent the standard deviation of a sample.
بينما يمكن استخدام أي منهما لتمثيل الانحراف المعياري لعينة.
This same pattern continues.
يستمر هذا النمط نفسه.
Here, you can see common parameters and statistics.
يمكنكم هنا رؤية المعلمات والإحصائيات الشائعة.
You can see the parameter and statistic values for
يمكنكم رؤية قيم المعلمات والإحصائيات
not only the mean and standard deviation but also for the variance,
ليس لمتوسط الانحراف المعياري فحسب، بل للمتفاوت،
proportions, and the values of coefficients and regression.
والنسبة وقيمة المعامل والتراجع أيضًا.
You'll see all of these in later lessons in the statistics class.
ستشاهدون جميع هذا في الدروس اللاحقة في فئة الإحصائيات.
This notation will be consistently used throughout these lessons,
سيُستخدم هذا المنهج بطريقة متناسقة في جميع هذه الدروس،
as well as beyond this course,
وبعد هذه الدورة أيضًا،
in books, blogs, and other use cases.
في الكتب والمدونات وحالات الاستخدام.